Finding Aid for the Peabody Dames Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Peabody Dames Collection
1917-1974
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0551
2.50 linear_feet
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains a miscellany of records (historical, financial, membership, press, and other) from this social club connected to George Peabody College for Teachers.
The collection is .84 linear feet and covers the years 1917 until 1974. In addition there is a scrapbook containing photographs, reports, yearbooks, and programs and which includes materials from the years 1953-1957.
- Notebook containing records of the Peabody Dames, 1917-1926 (Box 1, File 1)
- Articles of the “Peabody Dames” Constitution (Box 1, File 2)
- Constitution and Articles of the Peabody Dames with revisions (Box 1, File 3)
- Constitution and Articles of the Peabody Dames with revisions (Box 1, File 4)
- Constitution and Articles; Duties of Recording Secretary and Forms for Minutes (Box 1, File 5)
- Statement of Purpose - Draft (Box 1, File 6)
- Duties of Peabody Dames Officers; Hostess Needs and Assignments; Hostess Duties (Box 1, File 7)
- Yearbook, 1923-24; 1924-1925 (Box 1, File 8)
- Yearbooks, 1934 (Box 1, File 9)
- Yearbooks, 1952-53; 1953-54; 1954-55; 1955-56 (Box 1, File 10)
- Yearbooks, 1956 -17; 1957-58; 1958-59; 1959-60 (Box 1, File 11)
- Yearbooks, 1960-61;1961-62; 1962-63 (Box 1, File 12)
- Yearbooks, 1963-64; 1965-66; 1966-67 (Box 1, File 13)
- Yearbooks, 1972-73; 1973-74 (Box 1, File 14)
- Correspondence Record, July 1970 - April 1971 (Box 1, File 15)
- Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 1, File 16)
- List - Peabody Dames, January 17, 1934 (Box 1, File 17)
- Lists of names of members (Box 1, File 18)
- Peabody Dames Faculty List, 1970, 71 (Box 1, File 19)
- Peabody Dames Student List, 1970 - 71 (Box 1, File 20)
- List of Graduate Students at Peabody, Fall 1973 (Box 1, File 21)
- Guest List - Peabody Dames Tea, September 26, 1970 (Box 1, File 22)
- Peabody Dames Interest Groups - 1971; Useful information concerning available services - September 1971 (Box 1, File 23)
- “The Good Life on Little or Nothing” - in Nashville, September 1973 (Box 1, File 24)
- Dames Dispatch---Monthly Newslette, Jan. 1957; April 1957; undated (Box 1, File 25)
- “Peabody Dames Newsletter”, March 1974 (Box 1, File 26)
- “The Post” vol.xxvi no. 18, George Peabody College, Friday May 4, 1973 (Box 1, File 27)
- Newspaper clippings - Peabody Faculty Aid Dances and other (Box 2, File 1)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 2, File 2)
- Meeting notices, 1940 - 1943 (Box 2, File 3)
- Meeting notices, 1968 - 1969 (Box 2, File 4)
- Meeting notices, 1970 - 1971 (Box 2, File 5)
- Invitations to Peabody Dames addressed to Mrs. Alfred L. Crabb, 1935 - 1940 (Box 2, File 6)
- Invitation to tea at the President’s house, September 23, 1971; September 11, 1973 (Box 2, File 7)
- Invitation to Potluck Picnic, August 30, 19?? (Box 2, File 8)
- Invitations and programs - Peabody Women’s Club Guest Musical Tea, May 6, 1955; Holiday Party, Dec. 1, 1961; Fashion Show, March 2, 1962; Progressive Tea, April 9, 19?? (Box 2, File 9)
- Announcements - “Dames Farewell Brunch”; “Student Saved by Survival Kit”; “Peabody Dames Progressive Dinner”, May 11, 1973; “Poem” Feb. 1957 (Box 2, File 10)
- Invitations and notice of events (Box 2, File 11)
- Letter soliciting members, n.d.; October 1970 (Box 2, File 12)
- Ideas for Programs and comments (Box 2, File 13)
- Financial records and receipts (Box 2, File 14)
- Bank record - Third National Bank (Box 2, File 15)
- Bank records - Third National Bank (Box 2, File 16)
- Bank records - Third National Bank (Box 2, File 17)
- Bank records - First American National Bank (Box 2, File 18)
- Peabody College Diploma (Ph. T. - Putting Hubby Through) awarded to Wynne Egerton; Roberta Epstein; Nicki Fitzgerald; Helen Pitzer; Joyce Yeargan (Box 2, File 19)
- Peabody College Diploma (Ph.T. - Putting Hubby Through) - blank forms (Box 2, File 20)
- Peabody Dames Letterhead Stationery (Box 2, File 21)
- Scrapbook materials (Box 2, File 22)
- Scrapbook materials (Box 2, File 23)
- Graduate Orientation, September 5, 1972 (Box 2, File 24)
- Peabody College - General information (Box 2, File 25)
- Folk art and other brochures (Box 2, File 26)
- Program - The Trees of Christmas, Dec. 1972 - Tennessee Botanic Hall, Cheekwood, Nashville, Tennessee (Box 2, File 27)
- Photographs of the Fashion Show in February 1967: (Box 2, File 28)
  - Mrs. John Petry (Frances) (Folder 1)
  - Mrs. Cheatham Hodges (Joan) (Folder 2)
  - Mrs. Jack Susskind (Regina) (Folder 3)
  - Dames Valentine Banquet, February 1967 - all 15 identified (Folder 4)
- Peabody Dames Scrapbook (Box 3)
- This scrapbook covers the years from 1953 to 1957 and contains items such as invitations, photographs, newspaper clippings, the monthly newspaper, and the committee, membership, and program booklets from these years along with other items relating to the Peabody Dames. (Box 3)